If you don't use it, you lose it.
不用就会失去。
At least, that's how the old aphorism goes.
至少，那句古老的格言是这么说的。
It refers to the idea that something which does not get utilised regularly quickly falls into a state of decline.
指的是那些不经常被使用的东西很快就会陷入衰退状态。
For example, a hobby that you haven't done for a few years, like playing the trumpet.
例如，一个你已经几年没碰的爱好，比如吹小号。
You might find yourself a bit rusty the next time you pick one up - or maybe you've forgotten altogether!
下次你再拿起小号时，可能会发现自己有点生疏了——或者也许你已经完全忘记了！
Muscles are another example.
肌肉是另一个例子。
They will waste away without use.
如果不使用，它们就会逐渐衰弱。
In order to counteract this, people take regular exercise to keep their skills sharp.
为了应对这种情况，人们经常锻炼以保持自己的技能敏锐。
Well, what about the brain?
那么，大脑呢？
As we age, our brains can naturally begin to decline.
随着我们年龄的增长，我们的大脑自然会开始衰退。
In some cases this can lead to certain mental conditions such as dementia, which I‘m sure you will agree, no one wants.
在某些情况下，这可能会导致一些智力问题，比如痴呆症，我相信你也会认同，没人想要得这种病。
However, all is not lost because these days it’s relatively easy to train your brain.
然而，并非一切都无法挽回，因为如今训练大脑相对容易。
Smartphones and apps have put programmes into our hands that can test, maintain and even augment our memories, mathematical skills, logic skills and a raft of other mental abilities.
智能手机和应用程序为我们提供了一些程序，这些程序可以测试、保持甚至增强我们的记忆力、数学技能、逻辑技能以及许多其他思维能力。
With a little practice every day, we can keep our brains nice and sharp, right?
每天稍加练习，我们就能让大脑保持良好和敏锐，对吧？
Well, no, actually.
嗯，实际上并非如此。
According to a report from the Global Council on Brain Health, even though many people thought it was important to play online games, such as puzzles and mind games, which are designed to improve brain health, the evidence of the benefits was “weak to non-existent”.
根据全球脑健康委员会的一份报告，尽管很多人认为玩网络游戏，比如益智游戏和脑力游戏，对改善大脑健康很重要，但这些游戏有益的证据“很弱甚至不存在”。
Playing a ‘brain game‘ may lead to improvements in game performance, but this has yet to show a convincing result in people’s daily cognitive abilities.
玩“脑力游戏”可能会提高游戏表现，但这尚未在人们的日常认知能力方面显示出令人信服的结果。
In other words, doing hundreds of sudoku puzzles might make you a sudoku wizard, but it doesn‘t necessarily improve your ability to do your accounting.
换句话说，做几百道数独谜题可能会让你成为数独高手，但这并不一定能提高你做会计工作的能力。
It’s not all doom and gloom though.
不过，也并非全是悲观和绝望。
There are other ways to stimulate the old grey matter.
还有其他方法可以刺激年老的大脑。
It recommends seeking out new activities that challenge the way you think and are socially engaging, while leading to a healthy lifestyle.
报告建议寻找那些挑战你的思维方式、具有社交性，同时能带来健康生活方式的新活动。
Among their suggestions are practising tai chi, taking photography classes, learning new technologies, gardening, art projects or volunteering.
他们的建议包括练太极、上摄影课、学习新技术、园艺、艺术项目或当志愿者。
There‘s more good news, too.
还有更多好消息。
James Goodwin, chief scientist at Age UK has said that brain decline is not inevitable.
英国老年协会的首席科学家詹姆斯·古德温表示，大脑衰退并非不可避免。
As long as the activities are “new to you and require your concentrated attention”, they can provide benefits for brain health.
只要这些活动“对你来说是新的，并且需要你集中注意力”，它们就可以对大脑健康有益。
So, make haste, get out there and try something new.
所以，赶快行动起来，去尝试一些新事物吧。
Maybe it’s time to try that hobby you‘ve always wanted to do.
也许是时候尝试一下你一直想学的那个爱好了。
And as for me?
至于我呢？
I’m off to learn the piano.
我要去学钢琴了。